{
    "id": "e2dfc44b636440f390fffc932065acc0",
    "title": "Beginner Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "…………………….. fast, he caught the train.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Running",
                "Being ran",
                "Having run"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He is ……………….. proud to apologize.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "too",
                "so",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………….. we worked day and night we could not finish the project on time.",
            "description": "Although is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "Although",
                "However",
                "In spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Samuel ……………………………. was my classmate at school now works in Germany.",
            "description": "Use who to refer to people that cannot be used in non-identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………… running fast, I could not catch up with him.",
            "description": "Either despite or in spite of can be used here.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Despite of",
                "In spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I ran as fast as I could ………………………., I could not beat him.",
            "description": "However does not connect two sentences. It is a transitional adverb. Use a full stop or a semicolon before however.",
            "answers": [
                "however",
                "though",
                "but"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "7……………………… his leg injury, he played well.",
            "description": "In spite of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "However",
                "in spite of",
                "Although"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "………………… you do something about that letter from the taxmen, you will be in trouble.",
            "description": "Unless means if not. This sentence means the same as 'If you do not do something about that letter from the taxmen, you will be in trouble.'",
            "answers": [
                "Unless",
                "In case",
                "If",
                "Without"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked her why ………………………….. crying.",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was she",
                "she was",
                "she is"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The dishwasher ……………………………. I bought for my mother is expensive.",
            "description": "Either that or which can refer to objects in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The weather ……………………………… stormy, we cancelled the picnic.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "is",
                "being"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. you are my best friend, I don’t want any secrets between us.",
            "description": "As gives the reason it is similar to because and since.",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "Even though"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}